Someone out there, one of you has been
using my likeness to promote
cryptocurrency scams on YouTube. And I
will not stand for it. Yes, in part
because I don't want you guys to be
tricked or lose your money, but mostly
because of this.
What the hell is this? It's borderline
slander. That's not my setup. I swear
it's not me. A viewer sent me this
channel letting me know that they were
impersonating me, a so-called crypto
maverick, which uh just
beggars right to the heart if the
background wasn't uh slander enough. And
you can see they've been posting a bunch
of videos promoting cryptocurrencies.
It's all basically the exact same script
uh but using a different cryptocurrency
and putting me in a different
background. Uh here I'm in in IKEA. Uh
here I'm I'm DJing, I guess. Here. Well,
okay. This is my actual setup, guys. Uh,
not to brag, but I do have I do have
four monitors all showing uh AMC. So,
we're going to watch one of these
videos, and you'll see right away,
pretty easy to tell. Hey everyone,
welcome back to the channel. Today, I'm
diving into a high yield crypto
opportunity that's been turning heads
lately. I've been exploring a promising
token project that's currently offering
up to 952% APY. Yeah, just a cheeky 952%
return. Uh, no risk, guys, involved with
this. Staking a remarkably efficient
strategy to generate passive income in
the crypto space. Yes, you heard that
right. Minus 952% APY. That Oops, bit of
a slip up there. Yet, somehow still more
mathematically probable than walking
away from this with a positive return.
So, what's interesting is that this is
real footage of me from one of my videos
and the only AI that's being used from a
a visual standpoint is the lips to to
lip-s sync it. Um, and and the
background
the background as well also AI. Now, why
am I particularly excited about this one
specific token? Because it's currently
offering up to $952% APY. That's a
return rate you don't see every day.
Let's put it into perspective. If you
stake just $10,000, you could
potentially be earning around $265 daily
in token rewards. Sounds ambitious. It's
happening. And I've tested it myself.
Dot dot. So, here's what more do you
need, folks? I I've tested it myself.
period dot dot twice the the emphasis.
Anyway, you get the idea. That's the the
video. The whole thing is a tutorial
trying to get you to click the link in
the description and connect to your
crypto wallet, which uh I assume they
just take your money if you do that. You
can see the comments are all bots. Uh
you're my go-to crypto education now.
Thanks, guys. Appreciate it. And there
are videos being pumped out on a bunch
of different cryptocurrencies. All of
which are are actual projects. Uh some
of which I've catered, but uh you know,
trying to make it feel legitimate. Uh,
as well the link is a a sushi swap uh
spoof, so it looks like an actual
cryptocurrency exchange. Uh, which don't
click the link. Do not try this at home.
But I'll be done to make it again feel
legitimate. And well, you know, there
are some clear slip-ups with the audio.
It's not bad. Uh, the cadence is there.
It does sound like me. It's a little
flat. Uh, right guys, a little monotone.
Surely a model error there. Uh, but
it's, you know, considering it probably
took very little effort to put together,
it's pretty good. Now, of course, I'm
far from the first person to be AI
impersonated. This is an ad I actually
saw not too long ago of of Canadian
Prime Minister Mark Carney uh selling
some sort of fraudulent uh thing online.
I know Coffeezilla posted a similar
video of of ads of him circulating him
promoting some sort of cryptocurrency
project. We've seen Elon Musk, we've
seen Sam Alman, all these billionaires
promoting stuff as well. But what is
concerning here? Well, I think stuff
like this is a bit easier to filter out.
They've always had these types of scams
around uh celebrities and the like and
people with these public profiles. These
tools are being used to target people
privately, individuals who might not
have that sort of online presence.
There's this great report I found by
Resemble AI uh that found that a
whopping 34% of deep fake attacks
actually target private citizens versus
the 41% that target public figures. And
23% of these deep fakes are for the
intent of carrying out financial scams
or fraud. with there being over $200
million of just the documented financial
losses in the first quarter of this year
alone. So, while this video might be
easier to tell, it might be harder to
over the phone or something like that.
Um, you know, we've seen scammers uh
impersonate executives within companies
and internal communication to convince
people to route money. And I'm sure many
people have heard by now the kind of the
the awful extortion scams you see uh
where people pretend to have a loved one
hostage or something. Um, and what's
kind of crazy about all this is that
while obviously the more content you
have, when you have someone like me with
hundreds of videos online, you can kind
of build a higher quality model. I'm not
saying this one's high quality per se,
but it's possible to to replicate
someone better. But allegedly, it takes
just a minute of audio to produce a
model resembling someone's voice. So, it
can take just one recorded phone call or
one social media video to copy someone's
voice. So, while this is kind of a minor
case, you know, I've reported the
account. Hopefully, by the time this
video goes live, it's completely taken
down. Um, but something to be aware of,
you know, and I think it gives us an
opportunity to address that these types
of scans are becoming more common and
harder to detect. Used to be that you
had to be careful because anything you
saw in a guru video could be faked. Now,
the guru themselves can be faked. And
keep in mind, this is a pretty loweffort
video, right? With the completely
inaccurate desktop background and the
like. So, if someone takes a bit more
time or takes a bit more money, we're
going to start seeing a lot more
convincing stuff. I also highlight
quickly some tips for countering this
kind of stuff. I know most people are
probably thinking, "Hey, we're fully
adept to to handle this stuff. We're on
the internet, too. We're well aware of
all this stuff happening." But
personally, I know very intelligent
people who have fallen for financial
scams, so I'm still going to talk about
it quickly. One, pausing before taking
any action that involves payments or
exposing any sort of uh sensitive
information uh or potentially exposing
your your cyber security. to validate
the person's identity as best you can.
Uh, does the source appear legitimate?
Is the domain of an email or something
the legitimate domain for that company
or a very similar spoof? If it's a
corporate or law enforcement call, you
can also just hang up and then call
those institutions directly because if
you actually have an arrest warrant, uh,
they'll be happy to tell you over the
official line. And if it's a loved one,
trying to gain contact with that person
or a close trusted contact as well. And
some experts are highlighting the need
to come up with a protocol for this kind
of activity. uh something like a verbal
password or also if you can prepare
personal questions that only that person
would know that's not easily accessible
on social media uh that's another way to
try and verify uh someone's identity and
finally again don't do what I did avoid
suspicious links or documents quick
Google search can get you the actual
domain uh when you suspect that there
might be a spoofed one so yeah I just
wanted to share and take the opportunity
to talk about the broader topic of the
fast approaching dystopian future of of
AI trying to steal your money uh because
it is something that that we're going to
be seeing more and more of. I don't
think with this video it's a particular
risk. Again, uh as someone who's always
highlighting the risks even with
non-scam promotions from influencers and
the like, um you know, a bit
uncharacteristic of me to then turn
around and promote a 952%
return crypto project. I also take the
opportunity to highlight my actual
socials, which are the only places I
publicly post about stuff. Um, since I
also get a lot of of Twitter spoof
accounts and even YouTube accounts uh
that in the comment section will will
try to pretend to be me. And just to be
clear, I never have and and never will
promote a financial service, whether it
be, you know, a brokerage or an actual
investment, uh, let alone a a cratered
cryptocurrency. So, ladies and
gentlemen, this is what we've been
training for, right? As we march towards
the the promising future of generative
AI, good luck out there. Time to use
those critical thinking skills because
uh, we're in it, baby. This is the
endgame, so got to be vigilant. Anyway,
thanks for joining me today and as
always, be safe out there.
dot dot